Guide to the The Discussion Group, Houston, TX scrapbook and records, 1947-2019 MS 507
Woodson Research Center, Rice University, Houston, Texas
The Discussion Group, Houston, TX, scrapbook and records
1947-2019
Woodson Research Center, Rice University, Houston, Texas https://library.rice.edu/woodson
The Discussion Group (Houston, Tex.); Fleming, Mrs. Lamar; Houston, Mrs. William (Mildred White)
MS 507
1.5 Linear Feet (3 boxes)
This collection contains a scrapbook that includes the history, lists of members, programs, photographs, and clippings from the Houston, TX Discussion Group. The scrapbook catalogues the club's list of members from 1947-1994. The chronologically arranged folders in box 2 includes annual communications, program information and rosters, 1990-2019.
Biographical / Historical
The Discussion Group, Houston, TX was founded in 1947 by charter members Mrs. Lamar Fleming (wife of a Rice Institute Board Member) and Mrs. William Houston (wife of the President of the Rice Insitute). Early members researched world issues and the group discussed them - after the 1950s the group frequently brought in speakers.The Discussion Group grew into a significant "town and grown" group of members from the Rice and Houston area community. The Discussion Group modeled itself after the League of Women Voters - women gathered to research and discuss current event and issues.
Scope and Contents
This collection contains a scrapbook that includes the history, lists of members, programs, photographs, and clippings from the Houston, TX Discussion Group. The scrapbook catalogues the club's list of members from 1947-1994. The chronologically arranged folders in box 2 includes annual communications, program information and rosters, 1990-2019.
Conditions Governing Access
This material is open for research.
Conditions Governing Access
Stored offsite at the Library Service Center and require 24-hour notice for retrieval. Please contact the Woodson Research Center at 713-348-2586 or woodson@rice.edu for more information.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
This collection was donated to Fondren by Mrs. Ira Gruber on August 27, 2004, 2011, and 2019.
Contributors
Mrs. William Houston, Mrs. Lamar Fleming, Mrs. Ira Gruber
Index Terms
Subjects
Politics and government
Document Types
scrapbooks
Places
Texas -- History, Local.
- Series I: Scrapbook for The Discussion Group, Houston, Texas, 1947-1994; 37818; 0 Linear Feet
  Scope and Contents
  1 small box contains 1 scrapbook with member lists, a brief history, and photos of the group.
  - The Discussion Group, Houston, TX, Scrapbook, 1947-1994; 58229 (Box 1, Item 1)
- Series II: History and general business files
  - Historical background, 1947- (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Membership nominations (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Member and spouse biographical information (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Officers rosters, 1965-2002 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Duties of officers (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Speaker information (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Financial (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Special events (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Correspondence (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Notes (Box 2, Folder 10)
- Series III: Annual communications, program information and rosters, 1959-2017; 133225
  - 1959 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - 1963-1964 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - 1965-1966 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - 1967-1968 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - 1969-1970 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - 1970-1971 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - 1971-1972 (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - 1974-1975 (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - 1975-1976 (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - 1976-1977 (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - 1978-1979 (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - 1979-1980 (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - 1980-1981 (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - 1981-1982 (Box 2, Folder 24)
  - 1982-1983 (Box 2, Folder 25)
  - 1983-1984 (Box 2, Folder 26)
  - 1984-1985 (Box 2, Folder 27)
  - 1985-1986 (Box 2, Folder 28)
  - 1986-1987 (Box 2, Folder 29)
  - 1987-1988 (Box 2, Folder 30)
  - 1988-1989 (Box 2, Folder 31)
  - 1989-1990 (Box 2, Folder 32)
  - 1990-1991, 133226 (Box 2, Folder 33)
  - 1991-1992, 133227 (Box 2, Folder 34)
  - 1992-1993, 133228 (Box 2, Folder 35)
  - 1993-1994, 133229 (Box 2, Folder 36)
  - 1994-1995, 133230 (Box 2, Folder 37)
  - 1995-1996 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - 1996-1997 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - 1997-1998, 133231 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - 1998-1999, 133232 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - 1999-2000, 133233 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - 2000-2001, 133234 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - 2001-2002, 133235 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - 2002-2003, 133236 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - 2003-2004, 133237 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - 2004-2005, 133238 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - 2005-2006, 133239 (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - 2006-2007, 133240 (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - 2007-2008, 133241 (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - 2008-2009, 133242 (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - 2009-2010, 133243 (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - 2010-2011, 133244 (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - 2011-2012 (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - 2012-2013 (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - 2013-2014 (Box 3, Folder 19)
  - 2014-2015 (Box 3, Folder 20)
  - 2015-2016 (Box 3, Folder 21)
  - 2016-2017 (Box 3, Folder 22)
  - Obituaries (Box 3, Folder 23)
  - 2018-2019 (Box 3, Folder 24)